Let's start off by talking about your
work or your studies. Do you work or
study?
>> I work. Um I studied architecture for 5
years and now I work um in the research
department um particularly focusing on
urban planning.
Um so in a way it's a little bit uh
different from my background in
architecture, but it still gave me the
basics to be able to do what I do today.
>> What was your favorite aspect of your
degree?
>> Um I think it's a very creative degree
in the sense that you get to learn so
many skills at the same time. You get to
do a little bit of drawing, a little bit
of creative thinking, a little bit of uh
model making. Uh so in that way it
really makes you a one full rounded
person.
Um and um I think that's probably is the
thing that I'm most grateful for
throughout my my studies.
>> If you could go back in time and do a
different degree, what would it be?
>> I actually thought about that a lot. Um
I think I always was a little bit more
uh
uh less creative oriented and more
technical oriented. So um I would have
loved to do anything related to research
in the biomedicine area or the um
I I at some point even thought of doing
some engineering degrees. So something
maybe a little bit less creative and
more um
logical logical mindset oriented uh
discipline.
>> Do you think that you will ever do a
postgraduate degree in the future?
>> I have done my masters already in
architecture itself. If you're asking
about a PhD,
I think for my particular discipline
it's a little hard to do a PhD in
architecture um simply because again
it's it's more of a creative endeavor.
So um and a PhD is more of a research
oriented. So unless you try to find a
good um research topic in architecture
um
that I would definitely do it. Uh until
then I don't really feel the need to do
it just for the sake of doing it.
>> Now let's talk about your home. Do you
live in an apartment or a house?
>> I live in a studio apartment here, but
back home where my family is, we live in
like a slightly bigger apartment, a
three-bedroom apartment.
So, yeah. I
actually never lived in houses. I'm
definitely more of an apartment
apartment person.
>> And can you describe your family home?
>> Yes. So, it's actually a rather spaced
even spaced apartment in the sense that
it has
all the living rooms and all the common
spaces are large enough that we can
gather in it and have guest without any
issues. We have three bedrooms,
two bathrooms, and a very nice terrace
area that actually has a very
beautiful panoramic view of the city
and a little bit of a garden area, too.
So, very very grateful for the house.
It's been the the house that I lived in
since I was four. So, it's a little bit
run down around the edges, but
still I feel very nostalgic every time I
go back.
>> Is it a traditional house compared to
other houses in your country?
Just jumping in to give you our free
gift. We analyzed hundreds of Bun 789
speaking performances and we analyzed
the vocabulary. We've put all the best
words, phrases, idioms into one PDF for
you. If you would like that, go to the
description, click on the link. It's our
gift to you. You can download it 100%
for free.
>> I would have loved for it to be a
traditional house. Traditional houses
are back in my country at least very
beautifully ornamented, very beautiful
colors,
all of these riads and all of these
things, but
no, it's a definitely more typical
modern apartment. So,
no, not not in that sense.
>> Can you describe your dream home?
>> Yes. So, my dream home actually always
was for it to be as traditional as
possible going back to your previous
question. I always wanted to imbue some
of my roots um in my house. So, ideally,
I would love for it to have all of the
colors that I was talking about, the
beautiful blue bright colors,
um all of the patterns, and all of the
um
it has a very specific layout in that
you have the the the garden area in the
middle, and all of the other rooms
around it. So, I think that makes it
very um ga- family gathering-oriented in
that sense. Um
some some something like that would have
would be ideal for me, but we'll see how
the future what the future brings.
>> Now, let's talk about family gatherings.
In your country, what are the most
common times of year where families
gather together?
>> I would say is um all of the Muslim
national holidays. So, both Eids, um the
Eid after Ramadan, and the second Eid.
Those are common in all Arab Muslim
countries. Um other than that, the
typical New Year's, um and
our birthdays we try to celebrate
together, um
but that's not really cultural, that's
more of of our family uh traditions. Um
so, yeah, uh all of these.
>> And what food do you normally serve at a
family gathering?
>> It depends on the event. So, if it's a
um
uh like a
Muslim religious event, then it would be
anywhere between traditional sweets,
baroque and mint tea,
um
and those are typically what we have for
breakfast, and then for lunch or dinner,
we would have more of the uh
heavy oil
uh meals, such as couscous is one of
them. Uh
Chicken pastilla is one of them. Um
delicious, but
very heavy in that sense.
Uh but for birthdays, well, birthday
cakes.
>> And now, let's talk about hot drinks.
What's your favorite hot drink?
>> It's actually what I just mentioned.
So, I am Moroccan, so I love
Moroccan mint tea.
That's actually, I would say, our
national drink. We we We love to have it
for breakfast, lunch, and dinner, and
even a tea at any point during the day.
So, Moroccan mint tea, but but not too
sweet
because that tends to be pretty sweet,
actually.
>> Are there any hot drinks that you
dislike?
>> So, I I don't want to divide the
community out there. I'm not a big fan
of matcha or any of those trendy
hot drinks currently.
So,
that's a no-go for me.
Other than that, I I wouldn't
discriminate against anything else. I
love coffee, too. So,
yeah.
>> And if I visited your country, where is
the best place to get mint tea?
>> I would say the most traditional coffee
shops you can find out there. The
roughest coffee shops with the
roughest look and and the roughest
chairs.
Those tend to be The atmosphere there is
great, so you would get the the pure
traditional atmosphere in that sense,
but
any
Yeah, any I wouldn't say go to the
dangerous neighborhoods, either, but any
any of those. So, the original plan that
I have was back when I was 18, I had
planned to study continue my studies in
France. Um still architecture. Um
however, I I because continuing your
studies in France is such a common
pathway for every Moroccan out there, I
I wanted to try something different. I
wanted to experience a new culture, and
I wanted to learn a new language,
particularly. So, I rather shifted my
focus to more of a a new path. I wanted
to study in the UK, and I do not regret
that decision
not even one bit. I I feel very grateful
that I got to experience
the British culture. I was actually
enamored by the British culture.
When I was 18, I I got to really
practice my English and
speak a new language and I think had I
not done that I would have probably not
been able to speak English still
fluently
today. Um so and also I I got to travel
a lot across the UK that I don't think
I don't think would have been something
that I would have done had I had I stuck
to my original plan. So I feel very
grateful about that.
I still
I still got to to visit France every now
and then so it's not that I it's not
like I completely ignored the country or
the other but I got managed to to do the
both at the same time.
Um and other than that I
in terms of of my studies themselves,
I would say that perhaps studying in the
UK gave me a better
exposure to certain universities,
a certain level of doing that specific
discipline in a specific way.
Um so
no regrets.
>> So we've been talking about a plan that
you made and that you changed.
Now let's continue to talk about plans.
Do you think it's a good idea to make
plans with friends?
>> It depends on on the age I think. You
reach a certain age where even making
plans with friends
doesn't guarantee that you would
actually end up going to the or sticking
to the plan that you originally made.
Um so I am at an age unfortunately where
I think it's better you better off
simply going with the flow and
or perhaps planning a day or two in
advance but
planning from my experience planning a
week in advance never really works out
or maybe it's just that that I I have
bad friends I don't know.
>> Do you think that it's better to discuss
plans with someone or to keep it to
yourself?
>> Well, I'm a big believer in
keeping your plans to yourself
particularly they're very personal
particularly if they're aspirational.
I think you should really let your
actions speak.
>> [clears throat]
>> I I even I don't like listening to
people that that tell me their plans I'd
like to see them act on it. So I I would
probably keep my personal plans to
myself.
Yeah.
>> Now let's talk about
making plans for your career. Do you
think it's important to plan a degree
that leads directly into your
chosen career or not?
>> Also depends on the age.
At 18 you really you cannot know what
you want to do for the rest of your
life. So in that sense planning your
career is almost guaranteed to to be an
effort or an endeavor that doesn't
really amount to anything.
So I would not encourage uh
anyone at 18 to really plan their career
to the T
because more likely than not it's going
to change. So
um
it's important to to to go with the flow
and and be open to to any new
opportunities because you really don't
know I think when you're that young what
you want to spend your the rest of your
life doing.
So in that sense planning your career
particularly educational educational
path
is is not the best idea but it's good to
have a baseline nonetheless
and a little bit of leeway in between.
>> Do you think that it's essential for
someone to get experience in a career
they hope to go into or should they just
go into that career?
>> Definitely and I wish that that's
something that
as students did more or schools
encouraged to do more instead of
asking them to make a decision at 18.
I think it would be very beneficial for
for everybody to spend a couple of
months
doing the different things all at once.
Foundation year I think is something
that the UK does.
That that I wish I had done that because
I think
particularly at that age it's very
important to get to experience so many
different things. Really getting
hands-on on very different disciplines
and then making
an informed decision based on your
experiences rather than simply imagining
what could have could be good for you or
not.
>> Once somebody embarks on a career, if
they become unhappy, should they stay
the course or should they change
careers?
>> That's a very controversial question.
I think people have different
approaches.
So
I don't want to really disencourage
anybody to to quit but um
It depends again also on your
responsibilities. I think it's harder
when you have a family, when you have
people to take care of to to simply
act on a rash and and and leave your
career.
So where you're at an age where you
don't really have as many
responsibilities I would say yes.
Life is short. Why would you why would
you stick to something that that you're
unhappy doing?
>> I'll give you some feedback on part one,
part two, and part three and then we'll
talk about your scores. If you would
like your speaking assessed one-on-one,
we do offer that as part of our VIP
package. To thank you for watching the
video, I'll offer you 10% off. All you
have to do is just go to the
description, click the link, and you can
get 10% off today. So So, part one was
excellent. You answered every question,
and then developed it. Um
we've already discussed this, but it did
feel like a conversation. It felt like
we were getting to know each other,
rather than me peppering you with
questions. It didn't feel like an
interrogation, where you're trying to
extract the the language out of someone.
It just felt like getting to know you,
which which was excellent. Um if you do
that in the real test, you'll be
absolutely fine. Bear in mind that not
every examiner will be friendly.
Um some of them are tired, some of them
are just grumpy, cuz that's the way they
are. Um
they're not told to be friendly, they're
told to
assess the test accurately. Most of them
will be friendly, but sometimes you get
someone on a bad day, and it goes from
them you feeling like this is a
conversation, to oh, they don't want me
to be here. If that happens, just
pretend I'm sitting there, and pretend
that it's a
or pretend it's a friend you're talking
to. Part two, I thought was excellent.
You you talked you clearly stated I was
thinking of doing this. Here's the
reason why I chose it. Here's what
happened after. So, it was definitely
about the topic that you were asked to
talk about. You spoke for about 1 minute
35 seconds, and then you realized, oh, I
it's not 2 minutes yet. Did it feel like
2 minutes?
>> No, I I actually misunderstood. I
thought you told me to stop, but I I No,
no, no. No, no, no, it was my mistake.
It was my mistake completely. But, I
should have continued until there was a
a clear sign.
>> The way they will stop you is very
clear. It'll be they'll take the card
away, or they'll be like this, or
they'll say, "Well done, that's the end
of part two." But,
you recovered very, very well. You did
exactly what you should have done, which
was look down, find out what to talk
about, and then start talking again. And
you did that very well. Um you did have
a little bit of
audible pausing
but that was natural when somebody
stops you talking and then you have to
talk again. So, no problems there. Part
three again was very very good. It's
unusual for me to say that part three
felt like a conversation.
It did. Part three because the questions
are more like academically inclined
uh, sometimes it can feel like
like a a university seminar or something
like that where you know, what do you
think about this? I'm not saying it was
bad in any way. Um, I'm just saying it
was unusual but it did feel like that. I
think that's a very very good thing. You
did hesitate from time to time but it
was small and normally
bad hesitation where uh,
is when somebody is trying to think of
the correct grammar or the correct
vocabulary. That was not you at all. Bad
hesitation can also be if somebody is
uh, really overthinking something. The
example I use is Elon Musk. If you
actually watch interviews with him, he
is very his fluency is not good because
he's thinking very deep. He's wrestling
with a lot of things. You don't do that.
You are just pausing from time to time
to like, "Okay, I'm going to talk about
this. Then I'm going to talk about
this." So, it's not unnatural pausing.
It is very natural pausing which is
which is fine. Let's talk about your
scores.
>> Mhm.
>> There's one thing that I'm a little bit
concerned about and then the others I'm
not concerned about at all. Let's talk
about the things that I'm not concerned
about. Your vocabulary is a real
strength. Um, for example, when you in
part two, you were talking about
changing degrees. You were saying, "I
shifted my focus. I don't regret it not
even one bit. I was really enamored with
the These are very very advanced ways of
describing things." And you not only did
that accurately, which is very
difficult, you did it appropriately.
Like, to say something like, "I don't
regret it, not even one bit." That is
very, very advanced. None of those words
are advanced.
>> Mhm.
>> But, together
>> Combination.
>> the is amazing. Cuz only native English
speakers or very high-level English
speakers who've lived in the UK
>> Mhm.
>> would be able cuz you've heard that
quite a lot. "I don't regret it, not
even one bit." You know?
>> [snorts]
>> Um it's not something that would be
taught in textbooks. I'm not saying
something like, "I love the UK. I was
enamored by the UK." Excellent. And most
of your answers had that type of
vocabulary in there. Not every sentence
had something like that, but you don't
need to do that um to get a band nine.
The thing I loved about your performance
was it was very appropriate when you
were doing that. So, excellent. Well
done.
>> Awesome. Thank you.
>> You did make some little slips every now
and again. Like,
>> Act on a rash and and uh
>> I think you made I acted rashly. Or what
what were you trying to say? I I think
you said I acted on a rash.
>> have.
Uh what was I trying to
>> a bit rash? It was a bit rash, you know?
>> Maybe that's what I was trying to say.
>> Impulse, probably.
>> That was the only thing I picked up on.
That that was an obvious error. But, to
get band nine, you can make little slips
like that and still get a band nine.
>> [clears throat]
>> If you were making that like every few
sentences, you were making a little
error like that, you wouldn't be able to
get one of the higher scores. Or if
every sentence had an an or every other
sentence had an had an issue like that.
But, that was the only one that I heard.
There might be more that I didn't pick
up on, but it's it's very the frequency
of your errors is very, very low. So,
that's an indication that you're at a
very, very high band score. Fluency and
coherence, excellent. Your fluency is
very natural. Um your pausing is very
natural. It does happen from time to
time, but it is it is absolutely fine.
Your coherence is very good. You're
answering the questions. You're
developing your answers. Your
pronunciation is the thing that I'm a
little bit concerned about, but not what
you would think. Can you guess what I'm
going to say?
>> So, my pronunciation, I think where it
stands is that it's a bit of a mixture
between
uh
>> I'm not talking about accent.
>> Oh, not accent. Pronunciation. Um
no, enunciation?
>> Exactly.
>> Okay.
>> So, sometimes your voice is extremely
low.
>> Mhm.
>> So, for example, when you were said the
word matcha
>> I'm not a big fan of matcha.
>> I just about got that.
>> Okay.
>> Cuz you you you barely breathed, did I?
>> [laughter]
>> So, a lot of
>> Story of my life.
>> A lot of people have this issue. I used
to have this issue when I was a child.
So, even when I was speaking English,
people couldn't understand me cuz I was
very shy. So, I would speak low because
I didn't have the confidence. I didn't
want people to hear what cuz I was
afraid of being criticized.
>> Mhm.
>> So, I would speak inside my mouth. I've
obviously got over [laughter] that. But,
how I do that is um or how you could do
that. The examiner will probably not be
this close. They'll probably
It it it differs from test center to
test center, but could be this close,
could be a little bit farther back.
Imagine I'm sitting at the wall.
>> Right.
>> And speak to me as if I'm speaking at
the wall. That will force you to
enunciate and and to say your words This
It's just a volume issue. You're not
doing what a lot of people do, which is
speak like really speaking inside your
mouth, which affects pronunciation. Your
pronunciation is actually perfect. It is
literally the volume. So, you just need
to turn the volume up a little bit.
>> Mhm.
>> But, have you got that feedback before?
>> Yeah, that's why I said story of my
life. That's That's something that I get
very often. Uh it probably is um I don't
know if it's if it makes sense to say
that I was born this way, but it
probably is a like a force of habit, I
think, that I speak very low anyways on
a day-to-day basis. Um so, yeah, good to
know.
>> What the examiner will be thinking is
for pronunciation, can I understand what
she is saying? Can I understand each
word? I could understand every single
word, but you never know on test day,
two things could happen. Number one, you
could be farther away from the examiner,
that often happens, and they won't be
able to hear you. They won't really
consider that, oh, that's a volume issue
or that's a confidence issue cuz they
can't ask you about that the way we're
talking about it. They'll just consider
that a pronunciation issue.
>> Mhm.
>> I'm not saying you need to change your
voice for your life in general.
Um, I'm just saying for that 15 minutes
of the test, speak through the back of
the
>> Okay.
>> of their head.
>> And
don't give them any chance to to give
you a lower score.
>> Okay.
>> Your pronunciation is great. Every
single word I can understand. And the
great thing about your pronunciation is
you don't sound British or American,
you're not trying to fake an accent or
anything like that, which I think is
great. You can tell you're from Morocco,
you've learned English, and it's very,
very clear. All right? So, and that's
excellent. And you're also using good
intonation and sentence stress. Like
your voice is naturally going up and
down to convey meaning. It's excellent.
Just speak speak to them louder. Any
questions about that?
>> Louder. Um, well, the thing is for for
certain people sometimes who have a
naturally low voice, sometimes trying to
kind of almost force that that little
bit of a louder voice can be a little
bit distracting, and it can be a little
bit um,
sometimes even affect the the way that
you pronounce certain words. How how do
you get around that?
>> That is an excellent question. I know
what you mean because
our brains are not good at multitasking.
So, our brains are not good at thinking,
have I answered the question?
How's my vocabulary? How's my grammar?
Um, and on top of that, am I speaking at
a volume where he or she could hear me?
The way I teach is we want to actually
stop you thinking as much as possible.
The fewer things you think about, the
better your score is going to be.
Whenever you're speaking to your friends
or your family, you're not thinking at
all. That is when you are most fluent.
That is when your language is at at its
best because you're not conscious.
We want you speaking kind of
subconsciously. You're not consciously
thinking about what to say. So, I
understand your point and because we
we if you're consciously thinking about
volume, that could affect your ability
to answer the question, your grammar,
your vocabulary. If I could devise, it
would be there are decibel monitors on
phones.
So, you could speak naturally and
practice and it will monitor the
decibels and it will give you instant
feedback whether you are speaking too
low and then if you practice it at that
like that, then you you'll get used to
it and it's like anything. It's like
learning how to drive a car. At the
start, you have to think
gears, mirrors, trying
after 10 years, you don't think about it
at all. Same with riding a bike. So, get
to the point where you're always at a
certain decibel level and then you won't
have to think about it.
>> Perhaps the way that I'll do it next is
imagine that I'm with my family outside
near a construction site and then I'll
just [laughter] speak very loudly. I
think that could help.
>> Just to give you a little bit of
confidence. It's It's like a few words
out of 15 minutes. It's not a huge
problem. It's the one thing that I think
you can improve. Overall, I think you're
at about nine.
>> Okay. Awesome.
>> But I'm thinking of
what would possibly drop you down,
that would be the only thing based on
what I heard today.
>> Okay. Thank you. I'll work on that.